## FARAZ KHADIVPOUR

@ khadivpo@ualberta.ca

**\** +1 438 979 8252

M 601 - 11720 103 Ave NW

**♀** Edmonton, Alberta

### **Professional Summary**

Passionate Machine Learning Engineer with 3+ years of experience in creating predictive models. Highly experienced in collecting, cleaning and analysing data using Python. Deep understanding of statistical techniques and data mining concepts. Highly motivated with an excellent academic background.

- Expertise in different ML algorithms such as linear and logistic regression, decision tree, KNN, etc. and deep neural networks.
- Highly experienced working with image data and sequential data.

## **Working Experience**

#### Machine Learning Researcher

Computing Science Department, University of Alberta, Alberta Machine Inteligence Institute (Amii)

May 2020 - ongoing

**♀** Edmonton, Alberta

- Collaborating with computer science researchers and stakeholders to solve challenging AI problems.
- Analysing the inner workings of the neural networks using keras and tensorflow frameworks.
- Proposing a novel interpretable AI method which makes neural networks more understandable to human users.
- Working on an explainable machine learning method on image classification tasks and credit card dataset.
- Working on state-of-the-art convolutional neural networks such as ResNet, AlexNet, and VGG.
- Dealing with different image datasets such as ImageNet and Cifar10.
- Designed a human subject study to evaluate our proposed method and analysing the results using Rstudio.

### Machine Learning Developer

#### Mechanical Engineering Department, University of Alberta. (NCBLab))

🛗 Jan 2019 - May 2021

**♀** Edmonton, AB

- Worked as a team member on a project for RWDI consulting firm.
- Designed and developed highly accurate ML models to predict a specific variable in wind tunnels.
- Dealt with geometric data extracted from over 120 constructions.
- Used pyCaret library to develop and evaluate different ML algorithms such as xgboost, ridge and lasso regression.
- Implemented python scripts to extract features from 3D building models in Rhinoceros software.
- Applied data preprocessing and used different dimensionality reduction methods such as PCA and autoencoders.
- Used different methods such as k-fold cross validation and grid search to perform hyper parameter tuning.
- Implemented accurate deep neural networks using keras and tensorflow.
- Created charts and plots in jupyter notebook to perform statistical analysis and visualized data using matplotlib.

#### **Graduate Research Assistant**

#### **Environmental Engineering Department, University of Tehran.**

🛗 Jan 2016 - Jan 2019

▼ Tehran, Iran

• Thesis: Optimization of the bio energy production from anaerobic digestion, using data mining and machine learning methods.

#### Skills

python
SQL
Tensorflow
Keras
tflearn
Pandas
NumPy
Sklearn
pyCaret
Matplotlib
Plotly
Seaborn

#### **Education**

# M.Sc. in Environmental Engineering University of Tehran

**2015 - 2018** 

▼ Tehran, Iran

## B.Sc. in Civil Engineering K.N.Toosi University of Technology

**2010 - 2015** 

▼ Tehran, Iran

#### **Publication**

- Responsibility: An Example-based Explainable Al approach via Training Process Inspection (Submitted to AAAI 2023)
- Khadivpour F, Guzdial M. Explainability via Responsibility. The 2020 Intelligence and Interactive Digital Entertainment (AIIDE) Workshop on Experimental AI in Games (EXAG). DOI: arXiv:2010.01676.
- Shayesteh AA, Koohshekan O, Khadivpour F, Kian M, Ghasemzadeh R, Pazoki M. Industrial waste management using the rapid impact assessment matrix method for an industrial park. Global Journal of Environmental Science and Management. 2020 Apr 1;6(2):261-74. DOI: 10.22034/GJESM.2020.02.10

#### **Certificates**

- Machine Learning Engineering for Production (MLOps) (Coursera Specialization by deeplearning.ai)
  Fall 2022
- Deep Learning (Coursera Specialization by deeplearning.ai)
  Summer 2022
- Machine Learning Technician
  Certification by Amii
  Fall 2020